Oh, right, you came for the wake.
Grandma's house has been
left unattended since she died.
I'm considering selling it,
I do come clean
every now and then
but I need to get it in order first.
Before calling
the pros
It'd be nice to have a guy's help.
Sure.
Sorry to ask you on your day off.
Nah.
I was just sitting around watching WeTube.
We're here.
Ichinose
This is it.
I thought I was good at going it alone
Would you prefer to go together?
Place
your finger here
Rent-a-Girlfriend
"Childhood Home and Girlfriend"
The front door's locked.
Mind if we go in from the back?
S-Sure.
This is Mizuhara's childhood home.
Haven't been here
since the wake
It didn't really hit me the last time.
And I was only here
for a minute
Depending on how you slice it, this may
be more valuable than her apartment.
She's doing her investigation,
key
so she invited me to
a more personal space?
key...
This feels tense!
Chills down the neck
Like I'm going to meet her parents!
Please let me have your daughter!
You're asking the front door?
Oh, that cover...
The water main
It's loose, so be careful.
This thing is always so heavy.
And... hup!
Come on in.
Sorry, the slippers are by the entrance.
Excuse me
Don't worry about it.
Wha?
The washing machine's ancient!
The creaking of the floor,
and the scent of bedding and incense...
The second floor's this way,
and that's the entrance.
If you want
to use it
The bathroom's next to the entrance.
O-Okay.
This feels so lived-in.
It's a lot older than I expected.
It's frankly run-down
The air gets stale when it's been
closed up for two months, huh?
It doesn't suit Mizuhara's
current image at all.
This
glamorous
girl
Better air the place out.
Not that I can tell her that.
This is the living room.
Before the pros show up,
I want to put all the
miscellaneous trinkets in boxes.
Height matters
I want to take down the curtains, too.
Wait, what?
Rocks? Why are there rocks?
They're not pickle weights...
And they're all over the place.
It's not some
big bonsai, right?
staaare...
Locks eyes with the rocks
Can I ask about this?
R-Rocks?
All the courage he could muster
Yeah, it's crazy, right?
That's my grandpa's collection.
Any time he'd travel anywhere for work,
he'd bring rocks from there.
Saying each one
was a memory
There's a bunch in the yard, too.
The stuff inside's the tip
of the iceberg, actually
This is all
I'd like you to gather them outside to
make it easy for the trash collectors.
This is what I need
the most help with
O-Oh, really?
His collection?
There's a lot
I see why you'd want
a guy's help for this.
But they're mementos...
and you're
dumping them?
I'll do the job, but...
Are you sure, though?
Will you keep them in
your Room 203, then?
What else am I supposed to do?
Not very sentimental, is she?
Yeah, no
I guess it is what it is
Let me show you the other rooms.
Th-Thanks.
Okay, shall we begin?
beam beam
We're working as one!
I'll do my best
I'll sort out what's needed
and what isn't while I clean.
Let's start with the tough one—
the living room
You start dealing with
the final boss, the rocks.
Put the trash in
the bags over here
Roger
Final boss?
My grandma was such a hoarder.
Where am I looking,
and in her family home, no less?!
Her ancestors
are watching!!
This is really some situation, though.
We're in her family home all alone.
Sheesh, it gets covered in dust so easily.
It's like I'm her childhood
friend or something.
Is that how much she's opening up to me?
We're all alone here right now!
Make me and my background all yours.
You've grown up so much.
Focus on your work, you dumbass!
There's a lot of rocks
What're you spacing out for?
Carry them out
Huh? Oh, sorry.
Wait, why are you sweating
so much already?
Don't get so conscious of her!
I am but a forklift
Damn, the bath's super old-fashioned, too.
I've only ever seen bathrooms
like this in old TV shows.
Mizuhara lived her life here
for the longest time, huh?
Wait, for a long time?
Lived her life here?
Which means high schooler Mizuhara...
bathed here?
I need to make myself pretty
for the one I'll meet someday.
Gyaaargh!
Huh? That sounded like
you dropped something!
I-It's okay. I dropped it on my feet.
I can't! It's sensory overload!!
Did you really think there
wouldn't be a bathroom?
Keep
Dump
No one ever said
it would be this hard...
This is actually hard labor!
Who brings home rocks?
What was her grandpa even like?
Way to trouble
your family!!
Think of the
consequences!!
But she really is so blasé about it.
I mean, not like
there's a better option
I'm sure her grandpa
did care a lot about these.
Normally, you'd get a bit sentimental
cleaning up an empty family home.
She's always calm and logical,
and she never lets her emotions win.
Will I ever capture
this iron maiden's heart?
I'll give it a real shot.
Do it for her!!
Don't show any
signs of fatigue!
Still, I just gotta do it!
You brought another rock?
From Iyo in Ehime!
Beat.
Midnight
A 20-hour, 20-minute round trip!
Please don't make it heavier
based on distance.
That's not even a rock!
It's a boulder!
Long-distance drives
Ooh, that hits the back hard.
You need to lie down.
I'll put a compress on you
You'll throw it
out again, you know?
Don't push yourself.
You're not young anymore.
That's right.
You could turn down clients
demanding such long-distance trips.
What? They're heading far away
late at night with no travel options.
They all have their reasons.
Not that I think I'm being
a hero or anything...
but for people in need, I can always
find the strength to fight through!
Almost done.
Just noticed
An altar?
Photos. That's her grandpa.
That means...
this one must be...
Oh, that's my mom.
But she died when I was four,
so I barely remember anything about her.
She didn't like taking
photographs, it seems.
That's about all we had left of her.
This is Mizuhara's mom.
She was really beautiful.
No surprise there.
She was Sayuri-san's daughter.
Okay, back to work.
It's gotten dark
R-Right.
She really is so chill about it all.
It makes sense, given she was
only four at the time.
I think we did a pretty good job.
A sense of pride
and accomplishment!!
I carried out all the rocks.
I've learned not to collect
rocks when I'm older.
Not me
It's so much cleaner now! Thanks!
Mwah!
Yeah, not happening
Rock
This is Granny Sayuri's room.
Mizuhara.
A photo album?
Oh, you're all done?
Over there?
Y-Yeah.
Really? Thanks a lot.
No problem.
Photo album, huh?
I found an album
I was sorting out the books,
but this one...
I just couldn't bring myself to dump it.
Of course.
We're so weird as a species.
I don't remember a thing about her,
but just because she was my mother,
I can't throw away any pictures of her.
I guess the one thing she's taught me
is to take photos with my kids.
So she does miss her mom.
Duh. I know it's Mizuhara,
but there's no way she isn't lonely.
But she's doing all she can
to look forward.
It's not weird at all.
She's your mother.
It's natural to feel that way.
stare...
Stare.
Wait, what?
Yeah?
Cute...
I wasn't fishing for sympathy, okay?
Even without a mom, I've had a good life.
Well, as thanks for giving birth to me,
I guess I could give her lifetime access
to a photo frame and display spot.
On my shelf
Good for you, Mom
I want to give her a hug.
Listen, Mizuhara! I'm serious about you!
I wanna be there for you for life,
no matter what I have to give up!
Your loneliness, sorrow,
strength, and weakness...
I'll embrace your everything.
They all fill the void in their heart
with work or significant others.
Can I not do that for you?
Can't it be me?
Huh? An earthquake?
Whoa, it's a big one.
Hey, watch out!
Y-Yikes!
I'll get off!
It's not what you think!
I didn't mean to...
Wait.
Rent-a-Girlfriend
Whoa, what's all this?
"Wait"?
I lost my balance and landed on her,
and I thought she'd send me flying.
But she stopped me from getting off!
Why, though? For what reason?
She's so tiny!
So frail that I feel like
she wouldn't fight me off.
Is she okay with taking me in?
Mizuhara...
Mizuhara!
You've got a leaf on you.
Oh, I did? My bad.
Sorry I was dirty
Anyway, I took out all the rocks.
But there's still cleaning to do,
so I'll get back to it.
Grargh! I was this close to exploding!
It was just like
some manga
What was with the "wait"?
What was with the clinging?!
A leaf? Really?
I didn't have anything like that
on me when I checked!
She was acting strange, too!
Was that part of her investigation?
This is hard! By which I mean I'm hard!
Rawr! A leaf! It had to be a leaf!
There was nothing
more than that!!!
That wasn't a very good excuse, was it?
Hisakata
Thanks for the help.
I'll pay you for it soon.
It's fine.
No, it's not.
I can't believe I went to
Mizuhara's family home.
It was just for
a few hours, but
Who'd believe that?
I was in her family home,
and I got to see her there.
I don't like it when people say,
"It's still cold out in April."
I feel like I've found a new side to her.
It's like this every year.
But at the same time,
I realized there must be so much
to her that I have no idea about.
Did her investigation get anywhere?
Going to her family home just
put my imagination into overdrive.
If only we could be a family together...
I want to know more about her!
I want to get to know her much better!
Do you have, like, an ideal
image of a married couple?
Huh?
I dunno. Do you?
Never thought
about it
Ugh! I hadn't thought about it, either!
Think about it first,
dude!!
Oh, uh, I dunno!
Loud
A couple who are lovey-dovey
until the day they die?
Super!!
And I mean
super, super!!
Like, they never fight or something.
How many points does that score?
Lovey-dovey, huh?
I guess that makes sense.
Did I pass?
Lovey-dovey
with Mizuhara...♥
Simple mind
But I think I'd want something different.
Failed?!
A couple used to be strangers at first.
There's no way they'd have
the exact same values.
Nobody's perfect,
so I'm sure they'd fight and get
on each other's nerves at times.
But...
if something fun happened seconds later,
they should be able to laugh about it.
That's the kind of family I want to be.
Mizuhara...
Mizuhara.
I think I'll go with that, too.
You just convinced me!
What the heck? You're so silly!
Talk about easily influenced.
I'll probably never forget this day
for the rest of my life.
L-Lay off!
I went to her family home,
and it had all this history.
While I was there, I could imagine
the way she'd lived her life.
I want to be with her,
and be there for her.
It was more than enough to make me want
to see what it'd be like to live with her.
We're finally home.
That was a lot of work...
Huh?
Wait, what's going on here?
What's this? That's a lot of people.
There you are.
Mini-chan?
Wait, you were together?
Where'd you run off to now?
Huh? Oh, it's not like that.
We just ran into each other.
Look at her lie.
Anyway, what's going on?
This doesn't look good at all.
Looks like we can't go
into the building anymore!
What?!
Wait, what does that mean?
It seems the whole building
started cracking everywhere.
The landlord came to each room,
asking us to evacuate.
It's an old building, so it didn't have
the latest quake resistance.
The gas and power lines are fine,
He said it was a
good time to rebuild
but it's really not livable, it seems.
Cracks? Resistance?
Hence
the fire truck
I knew it was run-down,
but I had no idea
it was this bad!!
Not livable? Are you kidding me?
It was fine
all this time
B-But why so suddenly?
That pushed it
over the edge
We just had an earthquake, remember?
Right, we did.
What's Mizuhara thinking right now?
What's with the pause?
Wassup?
Were you overseas?
Yeah, that was a pretty big one!
Wait, so we're supposed to move?
That's too sudden!
Apparently, it's fine to leave the
furniture and move it some other time.
But for now, the landlord
wants us to take our essentials
Ask the landlord
for details
and stay somewhere else starting tonight.
Tonight? That's impossible.
I tried to negotiate,
but he said he'd pay us extra to move out.
10 months' rent
B-But...
There's no law that forces us to move,
but apparently it's unsafe for real.
The owner decided it'd be better
to be safe than sorry.
This apartment building's going away?
I have to move? Seriously?
I can't live in my place anymore?
But that means saying goodbye to Mizuhara.
No!
It's over!!
Celebrating
homelessness!
Okay, bye!
If anything comes up, I'll drop it
in the group chat we just made.
Who could've seen
this coming?
Life is strange,
and I feel alive
Wait, who are you?!
Karaoke or something
Wanna pull an all-nighter,
all three of us?
Uh, why would we?
You must have
lots of friends
I don't think you'll have trouble
finding a place to go.
If I come bearing the viral melon bread,
I can stay for a whole week.
I pinged one of my
cosplayer friends earlier
You, Master?
Family home.
And you, Mizuhara-san?
I think I'll go back to my
family home for now, too.
I don't know after that.
That moving-out fee will help
with living expenses, too.
You're so positive,
it's almost psycho
You're so quick to change gears.
Better that than getting buried alive.
Okay, see you.
She's so blasé.
What about
our all-nighter?
Mizuhara...
For real? Are we seriously
gonna part like this?
Doesn't Mizuhara feel sad about this?
You lived here for two years.
Your entire college life was here.
We met here at this place.
It's not like I don't believe she'll
actually look into her feelings.
We still go to the same college,
and I have her contact info.
But we won't be able to run into
each other at home like we used to.
Let's be neighbors, fair and square.
Nothing good comes of us
not being neighbors anymore.
Honestly, if we were actually dating,
I'd suggest living together right now.
Mizuhara... Mizuhara!
But there's nothing I can do.
I'll get going, too.
Cruel world!!
dun
Wait, who is this?
This is Saifur.
He's from the Philippines.
Hello.
Wow, you're so big.
His name means
"Sword of truth" in Malay
He's been working part-time at our store
for the last month and a half.
I'm letting him stay in your room.
Wait, my room?!
Don't assume you'll
have your grandmother
and your room forever
You're not
using it
But of course.
Besides, what about my angel?
If your building was being torn down,
why couldn't you suggest living together?
This is the
problem with you
You gutless boy.
Yeah, no, I don't have unlimited courage.
Asking the impossible again...
Know that you can't stay forever.
But hey, I guess that makes sense.
It's been two years since I left home.
He's a real hard worker.
Time is heartless
Of course everything's changing.
I'll look for a new place
Everything's destroying my mental state.
while I eat...
Mizuhara! Mizuhara!
Come back to me!!
Harumi-san,
is the nasi goreng done?
Almost done
That's a lot of stuff, girl.
Got nowhere to go?
Leave me alone.
You failed!
You need to target a meeker girl.
One who'd go
with the flow
That one's too headstrong.
Oh, wek-a-pepo, wake up people, Ieyasu?
Use Incineroar on Garchomp. Healthy.
Okay, you two take care.
O-Okay.
She's so chill.
There, there, Master.
Let's be streamers with no address.
No way!
But if Mizuhara-san
sees you on the streets,
she'll go, "I feel so bad! I need to
marry him and take him in."
Or not. Never.
Have more confidence in yourself.
Anyway, next time on Rent-a-Girlfriend:
"Moving and...
...Girlfriend."
Listen, Master! Don't go
stalking Mizuhara-san, okay?!
"Moving and Girlfriend"
I won't!
You're still at it?